<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-05-04T05:53:39+00:00</updated><id>https://jasonwilczak.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Back Again</title><link href="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2023/back-again/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back Again"/><published>2023-03-17T11:26:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-17T11:26:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2023/back-again</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2023/back-again/"><![CDATA[<p>So I was really determined in 2018 and wrote 100k book on my cell phone while I road the bus to work every day. It was an amazing experience, but I learned that getting published was actually going to be the hard part. I hit a few road blocks and stumbled a bit on getting any bites or interest. Additionally, I got some feedback from beta readers and took all the information to heart and got back to work.</p> <p>Then we got hit by a pandemic….</p> <p>You would think that being home and basically locked inside would have been the perfect situation for writing! Unfortunately, the way my writing process worked caused me to completely de-rail. I simply couldn’t find the words and the determination to literally do anything. That sort of bundled up with the changes I needed to make, the steam just stopped…</p> <p>Well, here I am again, I’m back. I got a new laptop that I can use unplugged, which is nice, and I started getting back into D&amp;D with my kids. Suddenly, the inspiration is back and I am ready to make progress again. Here we go!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="simple-posts"/><category term="simple"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[getting back into the swing]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</updated><id>https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Track and Focus</title><link href="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2018/track-and-focus/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Track and Focus"/><published>2018-01-02T11:26:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-02T11:26:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2018/track-and-focus</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2018/track-and-focus/"><![CDATA[<p>Getting back into the swing of things after a, much needed, holiday break. Picking up on book 2 and still working through the high level outline. I feel like I’m hitting a bit of a wall in plot and character development, though :/ I know where I want the story to go, but i’m afraid i’m rushing the journey, but I don’t want to fluff the adventure with unnecessary filler also.</p> <p>So, a couple of questions:</p> <p>1) How do you stay on track? -What methods do you use to reach your end state while providing enough color and fill to keep the story full?</p> <p>2) How do you keep the focus? -Maintenance of plot, places, people, creatures, lore, etc. It can get overwhelming!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="simple-posts"/><category term="simple"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[getting back into the swing]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Query (from a novice)</title><link href="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/how-to-query/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Query (from a novice)"/><published>2017-12-20T22:16:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-20T22:16:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/how-to-query</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/how-to-query/"><![CDATA[<p>So, someone on Twitter reached out to me regarding the query process and was hoping to get some advice. Now, I don’t think there is any silver bullet for querying, but I did find some resources that I thought were helpful when I first started going and I wanted to share them here:</p> <h1 id="the-query">The Query:</h1> <p>In short, this is your elevator pitch. You have 30 seconds to capture a complete random strangers attention. But, it’s harder than that, you have to do it while everyone else is screaming their pitch at them too.</p> <h1 id="the-process">The Process:</h1> <p>Here is the link that really helped me out. She breaks the query down into a template format that I found is really helpful when you first get started. It also allows you to separate re-usable parts from custom, per agent, parts.</p> <p>This is another link that also helps break the process down and emphasis one key aspect: personalization. As I mentioned above, you are a nameless face, in a crowd of people yelling your idea at one person. When you personalize your query (following the formats), you give a reason for an agent to look at you. So far, every time I’ve personalized a query, I have received a non-generic response from the agent.</p> <h1 id="the-example">The Example:</h1> <p>Now, I’m certainly not an expert in the field, but I thought it would be helpful if I pasted my first query that I wrote to my “dream” agent. Ultimately, I was rejected, but I received really helpful feedback from her.</p> <p>Dear Mx. X,</p> <p>Your passion for fantasy, science fiction, and relationships across characters from diverse backgrounds immediately grabbed my attention. Those specific interests motivated me to reach out to you in regards to my novel, Gemini Saga: Awakening. This is the first book of a planned series known as, The Aaxym Chronicles.</p> <p>Awakening is the initial gateway and foundation for the planet of Aaxym. The story revolves around a young man, named Aleric, and his journey of adventure, heroism and self, from his small village to the far reaches of his world. His life is disrupted by a corrupt king, driven by a darker entity that seeks to sway the balance of power in his favor. He is quickly accompanied by a female soldier, a tiger-human hybrid, that defies her allegiances to align her cause with his. Together, they make their way north, to the goddess of light, where the reality of their world starts to unfold.</p> <p>Empowered, and reinforced with others, they make their way south to put a stop to the corruption that continues to spread across the land. With each passing day, the group encounters gods, goddesses, dragons, and the undead. The greatest battles, though, are still ahead and, by the end of Awakening, Aleric realizes he will need to leverage the very existence of his species, the Dragoons, and all of Aaxym’s strengths to overcome the darkness within.</p> <p>As a fellow gamer, you may come to appreciate some of the inspirations that come from the variety of stories found in role playing games and the tone is intended to follow in that light. I believe the overall narrative of Awakening and, eventually, the series itself will connect with readers that enjoy titles that straddle both sci-fi and fantasy. At just about 100,000 words, the novel is an introduction to the world of Aaxym and its history.</p> <p>Thank you very much for your time,</p> <p>Jason Wilczak</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="simple-posts"/><category term="writing"/><category term="simple"/><category term="writing"/><category term="query"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[how to write a query]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Novel Length</title><link href="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/novel-length/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Novel Length"/><published>2017-12-20T22:16:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-20T22:16:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/novel-length</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/novel-length/"><![CDATA[<p>So, I received a question from someone about novel length and wanted to quickly share my experience in the same topic.</p> <p>As I got closer to completion and began the querying process, I found myself trying to understand how long the average novel is.</p> <p>Resoundingly, that answer is: 80k – 120k words. The short answer is that is a good length that keeps readers (and agents) engaged and follows a general standard. Certain books/authors have definitely deviated from this, and have been successful, but know that this is the rule of thumb many agents use.</p> <p><a href="https://www.writersandartists.co.uk/writers/advice/33/preparing-for-submission/how-to-find-a-literary-agent/how-long-should-my-ms-be">Here</a> is a deeper explanation on the topic, as well as <a href="http://www.writersworkshop.co.uk/Numbers.html">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="simple-posts"/><category term="writing"/><category term="simple"/><category term="writing"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[size does matter]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mob Authors</title><link href="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/mob-authors/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mob Authors"/><published>2017-12-17T22:16:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-17T22:16:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/mob-authors</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/mob-authors/"><![CDATA[<p>Hi all!</p> <p>I just setup the new Mob Author project over in <a href="github.com/mobauthors">Github</a>. The goal is to use Github and git flow to let a group of writers build out stories!</p> <p>Essentially, anyone can add/edit any file with whatever they would like. At the moment, it’s just me, however, as more people come on, they can approve, reject, or even request changes, with comments. Ideally, we could work as a group and build out an entire story!</p> <p>I put together the first one as a fantasy genre, no title and simply a chapter 1 file. I would like to have as many genres as possible and even multiple stories as different genres.</p> <p>What happens when we get a full story?</p> <p>Well, I’m think we try to get it published and Github will keep track of all the collaborators so we can work out a very straight forward process to ensure everyone gets equal recognition and compensation (if there is any).</p> <p>So, be the first to try out something brand new! <a href="github.com/mobauthors">MobAuthors</a></p> <p>If you would like to be an admin or take on a higher level position, reach out to me directly!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="simple-posts"/><category term="writing"/><category term="simple"/><category term="writing"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[crowd sourced writing]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sffpit</title><link href="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/sffpit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sffpit"/><published>2017-12-12T22:16:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-12T22:16:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/sffpit</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/sffpit/"><![CDATA[<p>Just heard about #SFFPit from someone I follow and got really excited! I just finished my first attempt at <a href="/blog/2017/pitmad">#PitMad</a> and, even though it didn’t result in anything, it was a fun experience.</p> <p>Now, hearing about this sci-fi/fantasy one, I’m really stoked. I just finished putting all of my pitches together and leveraged Tweetdeck to schedule them up (it was really easy and intuitive).</p> <p>I feel fortunate that i have 280 characters because that was hard enough to ram a 100k novel into with enough details to grab someone’s attention! Below is about what I plan on using on 12/14, let me know what you think!</p> <p>I’ll be posting a follow up to the experience as I watch it throughout the day. Each tweet below is schedule to go out at 1 past the hour, every hour, from 8:01am to 5:01pm.</p> <p>If you are interested in reading more about it, visit the site here: http://dankoboldt.com/sffpit/</p> <p>SCHEDULED TWEETS:</p> <p>Scheduled for: 8:01am · 14 Dec 2017</p> <p>FINAL FANTASY x HORIZON ZERO DAWN: A planet, powered by Xen, is under peril by one of its Guardians. Aleric is tasked with restoring order and, in the process, uncovers Aaxym’s secrets, with his species being the key. #SFFpit #FA #EF #FR #SNS #Aaxym</p> <p>Scheduled for: 9:01am · 14 Dec 2017</p> <p>His village destroyed by the corrupt empire and Aleric is thrust into #Aaxym with nothing but the clothes on his back. With the help of Rayne, a tigris soldier, he begins to understand there is more to him, and his world, than he realizes. #SFFpit #FA #EF #FR #SNS</p> <p>Scheduled for: 10:01am · 14 Dec 2017</p> <p>A corrupt Guardian, intent on shifting balance in his favor. A manufactured planet, driven by a power that radiates through it. A hidden hero, that unlocks the true reason for his, and his kind. A fierce soldier, who refuses to be a pawn. #SFFpit #FA #EF #FR #SNS #Aaxym</p> <p>Scheduled for: 11:01am · 14 Dec 2017</p> <p>In a world seemingly abandoned by its creators, one of its Guardians seeks to disrupt the balance of power. The others enlist Aleric &amp; his party to lead the fight &amp; find those they’ve lost. Their journey, though, reveals much more of their world #SFFpit #FA #EF #FR #SNS #Aaxym</p> <p>Scheduled for: 12:01pm · 14 Dec 2017</p> <p>Aleric is suddenly taken from his village by a corrupt empire. He learns that Onyx, one of Aaxym’s Guardians, seeks to disrupt the balance of power. Along with a small group, he navigates his world &amp; uncovers the truth about himself &amp; his species #SFFpit #FA #EF #FR #SNS #Aaxym</p> <p>Scheduled for: 1:01pm · 14 Dec 2017</p> <p>When a harvest festival is disrupted by a greedy empire, Aleric finds himself lost &amp; alone in the world. Only through the grace of sympathetic tigris soldier, he begins discover #Aaxym is on the verge of collapse &amp; he may be the key to saving it. #SFFpit #FA #EF #FR #SNS</p> <p>Scheduled for: 2:01pm · 14 Dec 2017</p> <p>Aleric, the son of a blacksmith, goes from carefree days on the beach to preventing Onyx, the Guardian of the Dark, from corrupting #Aaxym &amp; ruining life on the planet. Nothing could prepare him, though, for wanting to protect more than just his world #SFFpit #FA #EF #FR #SNS</p> <p>Scheduled for: 3:01pm · 14 Dec 2017</p> <p>Aleric, an unknown Dragoon, accompanied by Rayne, a tigris soldier and the last of her kind, push to save the world from collapse, and, in the process, uncover what motivates them to protect their existence. #SFFpit #FA #EF #FR #SNS #Aaxym</p> <p>Scheduled for: 4:01pm · 14 Dec 2017</p> <p>FINAL FANTASY x HORIZON ZERO DAWN: A planet, with a mysterious force, is under peril by one of it’s Guardians. Aleric is thrust into the role of restoring order and, in the process, discovers his species is the key to Aaxym’s secrets #SFFpit #FA #EF #FR #SNS #Aaxym</p> <p>Scheduled for: 5:01pm · 14 Dec 2017</p> <p>Corruption runs through all living things &amp; a Guardian, is no exception. But, where there is shadow, there is light. Aleric &amp; his kind were created to be this balance and through fate, #Aaxym has called him to arms. But even fate a double edged sword… #SFFpit #FA #EF #FR #SNS</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="simple-posts"/><category term="writing"/><category term="simple"/><category term="writing"/><category term="pitch"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[sci-fi & fantasy pitch event]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sffpit Aftermath</title><link href="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/sffpit-aftermath/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sffpit Aftermath"/><published>2017-12-12T22:16:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-12T22:16:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/sffpit-aftermath</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/sffpit-aftermath/"><![CDATA[<p>So, now that <a href="/blog/2017/sffpit">SFFpit</a> is over, i wanted to give a little synopsis of the experience and the end result of it all.</p> <p>First off, using tweetdeck was magical. I wrote up all my tweets ahead of time, as seen in #SFFPit !! (calm before the storm) . I then, of course, posted them to my blog and, through the help of some wonderful followers, received some helpful feedback! (mostly grammar, but still, invaluable assistance when you only have 280 characters to strut your stuff!)</p> <p>Most of the morning went by uneventful. I received a couple of likes from followers that don’t know the rules (emotions rose and fell very quickly upon those realizations 🙂 ), but then it came! A real like from an up and coming publisher: Fyre and Brimstone . Then, towards the end of the day, another like from a different publisher: Tirgearr Publishing!</p> <p>I reached out to both “likers” and let them know that I would need a couple days to put together their submission requirements and then got to work. As of last night, around 2am, I have submitted to both! I’ll do a follow up post to talk about my submission experience directly to publishers versus agents, as it was uniquely different.</p> <p>Bottom line: participate in any event you can. At the minimum, you gain some experience and at the maximum, you might get lucky!</p> <p>Below are the “winning” tweets:</p> <p>Liked by both publishers:</p> <p>Corruption runs through all living things &amp; a Guardian is no exception. But, where there is shadow, there is light. Aleric &amp; his kind were created to be this balance and through fate, #Aaxym has called him to arms. But fate can be a double edged sword #SFFpit #FA #EF #FR #SNS</p> <p>Liked by Fyre and Brimstone only:</p> <p>Aleric is suddenly taken from his village by a corrupt empire. He learns that Onyx, one of Aaxym’s Guardians, seeks to disrupt the balance of power. Along with a small group, he navigates his world &amp; uncovers the truth about himself &amp; his species #SFFpit #FA #EF #FR #SNS #Aaxym</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="simple-posts"/><category term="writing"/><category term="simple"/><category term="writing"/><category term="pitch"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[sci-fi & fantasy pitch event results]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pitmad</title><link href="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/pitmad/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pitmad"/><published>2017-12-09T22:16:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-09T22:16:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/pitmad</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/pitmad/"><![CDATA[<p>So, I get my twitter account all setup and I see this #pitmad post. So a little digging in and I figure out that it’s this whole event around submissions! My head is reeling, “perfect timing!” Work becomes ancillary and the daily hum drum of life becomes a distant fuzz, as all that is running through my mind is my 3 available pitches…</p> <p>First one was in draft mode right up until 8am…send. Back and forth, on and off, nothing. I see the tweets piling up against the hashtag, no big deal. Lunch comes around, my pairing partner having no idea that I could care less about the code at the moment. Boom, send again. Nothing…not even a retweet. Finally, the end of the day rolls around and i have a third (and best, in my opinion) pitch ready to go and I fire it off.</p> <p>Now, in retrospect, I’m not sure what I really expected. I’ve messaged about 10 agents so far, with no positive results and the folks on #pitmad are really good at catching your attention. But, I think I did learn quite a bit from the experience…</p> <ul> <li>My wife gave me some good ideas on how to target my pitches better</li> <li>Putting media titles that capture an idea of your book (Lord of the Flies meets Harry Potter) seems to really work well</li> <li>There is no magic solution to this except for time and a bit of luck</li> <li>On the plus side, I found some really great writers to follow and gained some more knowledge going forward. I’ve decided to release my first chapter on Wattpad and get some feedback, so check it out!</li> </ul> <p><a href="https://www.wattpad.com/505043055-the-aaxym-chronicles-gemini-saga-awakening-1">the-aaxym-chronicles-gemini-saga-awakening-1</a></p> <p>If anyone else has some experiences to share against #pitmad, I’d love to hear them!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="simple-posts"/><category term="writing"/><category term="simple"/><category term="writing"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[submission events on twitter]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Up and Running!</title><link href="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/up-and-running-copy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Up and Running!"/><published>2017-12-06T22:16:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-06T22:16:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/up-and-running%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jasonwilczak.github.io/blog/2017/up-and-running-copy/"><![CDATA[<p>Looks like the blog is up and running!</p> <p>I used Amazon’s Lightsail offering and it was a breeze!  I coupled it all with my Namecheap domain registrar and was up and running in no time.  I would suggest looking into it!</p> <p>I also came across Wattpad and feel like I’ve been living under a rock…looking forward to pumping out a few short stories!</p> <p>On top of that, working on that next book and looking for agents for book 1</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="simple-posts"/><category term="simple"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[finally got the blog up and running]]></summary></entry></feed>